

# Varvara Lazarenko

Address Nijmegen, The Netherlands Telephone

LinkedIn

+31 6 2662 9839

**E-mail** varlazoa@gmail.com Date of birth 29.12.1998 (26 years)

www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly motivated and hardworking graduate with a Master's degree in Medical biology. Having worked in fundamental research setting as well as in clinical trials development, I am passionate about societal & business aspects of healthcare innovations. With a strong biomedical foundation and a keen interest in sustainable healthcare, I envision a career in health technology assessment (HTA), value assessment, health economics, healthcare education or consultancy.

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2022 - 08/2024

# MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA 7.63/10.00
- ✓ Principal subjects: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Reaching the Sustainable **Development Goals**
- ✓ Projects: «HTA of a Medical Guidance App for International Students in the NL» «A Shared Ownership Model of the Green Corridor, Nijmegen» «A Circular Alternative to Single-Use Cups Within the Dutch Train System»
- ✓ <u>Master thesis</u>: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care»

09/2016 - 06/2020

### BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA 4.83/5.00
- ✓ Principal subjects: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Physiology of secretory system, Introduction to endocrinology
- ✓ Bachelor thesis: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats»

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

02/2024 - 08/2024

### **Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care**

# HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- √ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023

### **Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory**

# **Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands**

- ✓ In vivo Ca<sup>2+</sup> imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (mice, handling & feeding)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

# 08/2021 – 08/2022 Assistant at the Science department of the Contract Research Organization LABMGMU, LLC – Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- √ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

# 10/2020 - 10/2021 Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

# Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological and molecular biology experiments (wire myography, real-time PCR, western blot)
- √ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at two conferences (Oct, 2020; Apr, 2021)

### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, and MS Office softwares

## **LANGUAGES**

Russian (native), English (fluent –  $C_2$ ), German (intermediate –  $B_1$ - $B_2$ ), Dutch (low intermediate –  $A_2$ - $B_1$ ), French (beginner -  $A_1$ )

### ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

2022-2024	Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
2020-2021	Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
2021	Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

### **CERTIFICATES**

2023	A course on ex. Art. 9 of the Dutch Act on animal experimentation, Radboudumc	
2021	An upgrade training on ICH GCP guidelines, LABMGMU	

## **VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY**

2024	Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
2023	Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
2022-2023	Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
2018-2021	Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

### **HOBBIES**

Volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

### **JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., **Lazarenko Varvara S.**, Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. *Frontiers in physiology*, *13*: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- **2. Lazarenko Varvara**, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. *Artery Research*, *26*(S1): S58. <a href="https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048">https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048</a>
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., **Lazarenko V.S.**, Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. *Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina*, *54*(2): 89–95. <a href="https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639">https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639</a>